We are now ready to begin our next major topic, Program Optimization. In this
我们现在准备开始我们的下一个主要话题，程序优化。在这里面
video, we're just going to give overview discussing why we want to perform
视频，我们将给出一个概述，讨论为什么我们想要表演
optimization and what the trade-offs are for compilers and deciding what kind of
优化以及编译器的权衡是什么，以及决定哪种类型的
optimizations to implement. Optimization is the last compiler phase that we're
要实施的优化。优化是我们正在进行的最后一个编译阶段
going to discuss. Let's just very briefly review the compiler phases. First there is
我们要讨论一下。让我们非常简要地回顾一下编译器阶段。首先是
lexical analysis and then that's followed by parsing. Then we have semantic
词法分析，然后是解析。然后我们就有了语义
analysis. And after that we talked about code generation. And now we're going to
分析。在那之后，我们讨论了代码生成。现在我们要做的是
talk about optimization, okay? So optimization actually comes before code
谈论优化，好吗？因此，优化实际上先于代码
generation because we want to improve the program before we commit it to machine
生成，因为我们希望在将程序提交到机器之前对其进行改进
code but it is of course the last one that we've discussed. But, just point out here,
代码，但这当然是我们讨论的最后一个问题。但是，只要在这里指出，
optimization fits in between generally semantic analysis and code generation and
优化介于一般的语义分析和代码生成之间，并且
in modern compilers this is where most of the action is. It's usually has by far the
在现代编译器中，这是操作最多的地方。到目前为止，它通常都有
most code, and it's also the most complex part of the compiler. Now, a very basic
大多数代码，也是编译器中最复杂的部分。现在，一个非常基本的问题
question is, when we should perform optimizations? And we actually have some
问题是，我们应该在什么时候进行优化？我们实际上有一些
choices. We could perform them on the abstract syntax tree and, a big advantage
选择。我们可以在抽象语法树上执行它们，这是一个很大的优势
of that is that it's machine independent but for many optimizations we want to do,
其中之一是它是独立于机器的，但对于我们想要进行的许多优化，
this, it turns out that the abstract syntax tree will be too high level that we
这就证明了抽象语法树的级别太高，以至于我们
can't actually even express the optimizations we want to perform because
实际上甚至不能表达我们想要执行的优化，因为
those optimizations depend on lower level details of the machine or of the kind of
这些优化取决于机器的较低级别的详细信息或
machine that we're generating code for that aren't present in the abstract syntax
我们正在为其生成代码的计算机没有出现在抽象语法中
tree. Another possibility would be to perform optimizations directly on assembly
树。另一种可能性是直接对程序集执行优化
language and the advantage here that all the details of the machine are exposed. We
这里的优点是机器的所有细节都被曝光了。我们
can see everything that the machine is doing. We can talk about all the resources
可以看到机器正在做的一切。我们可以谈论所有的资源
of the machine and so, in principle, any optimization we want to perform can be
因此，原则上，我们要执行的任何优化都可以是
expressed at the assembly language level. Now a disadvantage of doing optimizations
用汇编语言级别表达。现在做优化的一个缺点是
on assembly language is that they are machine-dependent. And then we would have
汇编语言的特点是它们依赖于机器。然后我们就会有
to potentially re-implement our optimizations for each new kind of
为了潜在地重新实现我们对每一种新类型的
architecture. And so, as we mentioned in the previous video, another option is to
建筑。因此，正如我们在前面的视频中提到的，另一种选择是
use an intermediate language And the intermediate language has the advantage
使用中间语言，中间语言具有优势
potentially, if it's designed well, of still being machine independent. Meaning
如果设计得当，它仍有可能独立于机器。含义
it can, it can be a little bit above the level of the concrete details of very,
它可以，它可以比非常具体的细节稍微高一点，
very specific architectures. I mean, it can still represent a large family of
非常特殊的架构。我是说，它仍然可以代表一个大家庭
machines but while, at the same time, exposing enough optimization opportunities
机器，但同时也暴露了足够的优化机会
that the compiler can do a good job of improving the program's performance. So,
编译器可以很好地提高程序的性能。所以,
we will be looking at optimizations that work on intermediate language that has
我们将研究在具有以下特性的中间语言上工作的优化
operations given by this grammar. So, in this case, a program is a sequence of
由这种语法给出的运算。因此，在这种情况下，程序是一系列
statements and a statement consists of either, an assignment Which could be a
语句，而语句由任一语句组成，赋值可以是
simple copy, or a unary, or binary operation. We can push and pop things from
简单复制，或一元或二进制操作。我们可以从这里推送和弹出东西
a stack and then we have a couple of different kinds of jumps. We have a
一个堆栈，然后我们有几种不同的跳跃。我们有一个
comparison in jump where we compare the value of two registers and then
跳转中的比较，我们比较两个寄存器的值，然后
conditionally jump to a label. We have unconditional jumps and finally there are
有条件地跳转到标签。我们有无条件的跳跃，最后还有
labels, the targets of jumps. And the identifiers here are the register names,
标签，跳跃的目标。这里的标识符是寄存器名称，
and we could also use immediate values on the right hand side of operations instead
我们也可以在运算的右侧使用立即值
of registers and the typical operators, we're just going to assume some typical
寄存器和典型运算符，我们将假设一些典型的
family of operators like +,,, -,,, 'lt;i>, etcetera. Now, optimizations typically'lt;/i>
运算符系列，如+、-、‘lt；i>等。现在，优化通常是’lt；/i>
work on groups of statements and one of the most important and useful statement
研究语句组和最重要、最有用的语句之一
groupings is the basic block. So a basic block is a sequence of instructions and
分组是基本的挡路。所以基本的挡路是一系列的指令和
typically we want it to be the longest possible sequence of instructions. So we
通常，我们希望它是尽可能长的指令序列。所以我们
want it to be maximal and this sequence has two properties. First of all there are
希望它是最大的，这个序列有两个属性。首先，有几个
no labels except possibly for the very first instruction. And there are no jumps
除了可能的第一条指示外，没有标签。而且没有跳跃
anywhere in this sequence of instructions except, possibly for the last instruction.
该指令序列中的任何位置，可能除了最后一条指令之外。
And a basic block the ide a behind a basic block, and the reason we require these two
一个基本的挡路背后有一个基本的挡路，我们需要这两个的原因
properties is that it's guaranteed to flow, the execution is guaranteed to
属性是它被保证流动，执行被保证
proceed from the first statement in the block to the last statement in the block.
从挡路的第一条声明到挡路的最后一条声明。
So the flow of control within a basic block is completely predictable. Once we
所以在一个基本的挡路内部的控制流是完全可以预测的。一旦我们
enter the block, once we begin at the first statement of the block which might
进入挡路，一旦我们从挡路的第一句话开始，可能
have a label, there will be a sequence of statements. That must all execute before
有了标签，就会有一系列的陈述。它们必须全部在之前执行
we reach the last statement which could potentially be a jump to some other part
我们到达最后一条语句，它可能会跳转到其他部分
of the code. But once we get here, once we get to this very first statement, then
代码的一部分。但是一旦我们到了这里，一旦我们到了第一个陈述，那么
we're guaranteed to execute the entire block without jumping out And furthermore,
我们保证在不跳出来的情况下执行整个挡路，而且，
there's no way to jump into the block. You couldn't just come from some other random
没有办法跳进挡路。你不能随便从别的地方来
part of the program and begin execution, say, at the second or third instruction.
程序的一部分，并开始执行，比方说，在第二条或第三条指令处。
The only way into the block is through the first statement, and the only way out is
进入挡路的必由之路是通过第一条语句，唯一的出路是
through the last statement. Say here's a example basic block and just to show you
通过最后一份声明。假设这是一个基本的挡路示例，只是为了向您展示一下
why basic blocks are useful. Let's observ that we can actually optimize this piece
为什么基本块很有用。让我们观察一下，我们实际上可以优化这一块
of code. Okay because three always executes after two. This instruction here
代码。好的，因为三总是在二之后执行。此处的说明
always execute after this instruction. We could change that third instruction to be
始终在此指令之后执行。我们可以将第三条指令更改为
w = three x. Okay because we can see here that t is getting two x + x or two
W=3x，好的，因为我们在这里可以看到t是2x+x或2x
x and here we're adding in another x and so w is actually always equal to three
在这里我们再加上一个x，所以w实际上总是等于3
x. And a question then, so that, that is certainly a correct optimization and, and
x.然后是一个问题，所以，这肯定是一个正确的优化，并且
it's correct exactly because statement two is always guaranteed to execute before
它是正确的，因为语句2总是保证在
statement three. Another question we might be is whether we can eliminate this
陈述三。我们可能面临的另一个问题是，我们是否能消除这一点
statement so once we replace this by three x, you know maybe we don't need this
语句，所以一旦我们用3x替换它，你知道我们可能不需要这个
assignment anymore if this was the only place that t was used if t was a temporary
如果这是唯一使用t的位置(如果t是临时的
value that was computed only to compute the, the value w. And then we can delete
仅为计算w值而计算的值，然后我们可以删除
this statement and this depends on the rest of the program. We have to know
这句话和这句话要看节目的睡觉。我们必须知道
whether t has any other uses someplace else in the program w hich we can't see
程序中其他我们看不到的地方有没有其他用途
just by looking at the single basic block. The next important grouping of statements
单看一下基本的挡路就知道了。下一个重要的语句分组
is a control flow graph. And a control flow graph is a, just a graph of basic
是一个控制流图。而控制流图就是一个，就是一个基本的
blocks. And so there's an edge from block a to block b. If execution could pass from
块。所以从挡路a到挡路b有优势。如果死刑可以从
the last instruction in a to the first instruction of b. So essentially the
a中的最后一条指令到b的第一条指令。所以本质上
control flow graph just shows how control flow can pass between the blocks and there
控制流图仅显示控制流如何在块和块之间传递
isn't of course no interesting control flow within the block. We know that the
当然，挡路中没有有趣的控制流。我们知道
basic block will just execute from the first instruction to the last instruction.
基本挡路只执行从第一条指令到最后一条指令。
So, the control flow graph is a way of summarizing the interesting decision
因此，控制流程图是总结有趣决策的一种方式
points in a, in a procedure or a other piece of code showing where some
、过程中的点或其他代码段中的点，以显示某些
interesting control flow decision is actually made. So here's a simple control
实际上做出了有趣的控制流决策。所以这里有一个简单的控件
flow graph consists of two basic blocks. The first basic block is outside of the
流程图由两个基本块组成。第一个基本的挡路在世界范围外
loop, and consists of some initialization code. And then we have one basic block
循环，并由一些初始化代码组成。然后我们有一个基本的挡路
here in the loop. The basic block consists of these three instructions. And at the
就在这个循环里。基本的挡路由这三个指令组成。而在
bottom of the block is a branch, a testing branch where either we, exit and go
挡路的底部是一个分支，一个测试分支，我们要么退出，要么去
someplace else or we loop around and execute the loop body again, okay? And the
其他地方，否则我们再循环一遍，再执行一次循环体，好吗？以及
body of a method can always be represented as a control flow graph. The convention
方法体始终可以表示为控制流图。大会
that we'll use is always a distinguished entry node so a distinguished start node
我们将使用的始终是可区分的条目节点，因此可区分的起始节点
of the control flow graph and typically it'll just be obvious it'll be the one
控制流图的一部分，通常很明显，它将是
listed at the top. And then there will be some return nodes or one or some nodes of
列在最上面。然后会有一些返回节点或一个或几个节点
which you can return from and you know you have a return statements in the procedure.
您可以从中返回，并且您知道在该过程中有一个Return语句。
And return nodes or places where you exit the procedure will always be terminal.
并且返回您退出该过程的节点或位置将始终是终止的。
Meaning there will be no edges out of those blocks. Now, the purpose of
这意味着这些区块将不会有边缘。现在，我要说的是
optimization is to improve a program's resource utilization. And for the purposes
优化就是提高程序的资源利用率。并且出于以下目的
of this classroom, when we talk about optimization in, in our examples and in
当我们在、在我们的示例中和在中谈论优化时，
the videos we're gonna be talking about execution time. And we're gonna be talking
我们将要谈论的行刑时间的视频。我们将会谈论
about, we're g onna be talking about making the program run faster. And this is
关于，我们要讨论的是如何让程序运行得更快。这是
mostly what people are interested in. So most compilers do spent quite a bit of
主要是人们感兴趣的东西。所以大多数编译器确实花费了相当多的时间
effort on making programs run faster but it's important to realize that there are
努力让程序运行得更快，但重要的是要认识到
many other resources that we could optimize for. And, actually for any
我们可以针对许多其他资源进行优化。而且，实际上对任何人来说
resource that you can imagine there probably is a compiler out there that
资源，您可以想象可能有一个编译器在那里
spend some effort optimizing for an insert domain domains of application. So for
花点功夫来优化应用程序的插入域域。所以对于
example there are compilers we might care about code size. We might care about the
例如，有些编译器我们可能会关心代码大小。我们可能会关心
number of network messages sent, other things that are commonly optimized for our
发送的网络消息数量，以及通常针对我们的
memory usage, disk accesses so, so databases, for example. Try to minimize
内存使用率、磁盘访问量等等，比如数据库。尽量最小化
the number of times you access the disk and, and power for battery powered
您访问磁盘的次数和，以及电池供电的电源
devices. And the important thing about optimization is that it should not alter
设备。关于优化的重要一点是，它不应该改变
what the program computes. The answer still must be the same, okay? So we're
程序计算的内容。答案肯定还是一样的，好吗？所以我们要
allowed to improve, the program's resource utilization, but we can't change what the
允许改善，程序的资源利用率，但我们不能改变
program will produce. Now, for languages like C and Cool, and all of the languages
节目将会制作。现在，对于像C和Cool这样的语言，以及所有的语言
that you're probably familiar with, there are three granularities of optimization
您可能很熟悉，有三种粒度的优化
that people typically talk about. One is called local optimization, and those are
这是人们通常谈论的话题。一种叫做局部优化，它们是
optimizations that apply to a basic block in isolation. So these are optimizations
孤立地应用于基本挡路的优化。所以这些都是优化的
that occur within a single basic block. Then there are what are called global
出现在一个基本的挡路内。然后是所谓的全局
optimizations and this is really misnamed because it's not global across the entire
优化，这真的是命名错误，因为它不是整个全局的
program. What people mean by global optimization is that implies to a control
程序。人们所说的全局优化是指控制
flow graph. It's global across an entire function alright so, so global
流程图。它在整个函数中是全局的，好的，所以是全局的
optimizations would apply to a single function and optimizer across all the
优化将应用于所有
basic blocks of that function. And finally there are inter-procedural optimizations
该功能的基本模块。最后，还有过程间的优化
these are optimizations that work across method boundaries. They take multiple
这些是跨方法边界工作的优化。他们使用多个
functions and move things around to try to optimize the collection of functions as a
函数并移动对象，以尝试将函数集合优化为
whole. Many compilers do one, in fact almost all compilers do one. Many, many
完整的。许多编译器都会这样做，事实上几乎所有编译器都会这样做。很多很多
compilers today do two, but not very many actually do three, okay? So you see
今天的编译器做两个，但实际上做三个的人不是很多，好吗？所以你看
decreasing numbers of compilers doing, these optimizations as you move up in the
进行这些优化的编译器数量不断减少，当您在
granularity, and partly that's because the optimization's are more difficult to
粒度，这在一定程度上是因为优化更难
implement so it's just more work to implement the inter-procedural
实现，所以只需要做更多的工作来实现过程间
optimization's but also because a lot of the payoff is in the more local
优化的同时也因为更多的收益来自于更多的本地化
optimizations. So, expanding on that last point a little bit more. It turns out
优化。因此，在最后一点上再做一些扩展。结果发现
that, in practice, while we know how to do many, many optimizations. Often a
那就是，在实践中，当我们知道如何做很多很多优化的时候。通常是一个
conscious decision is made not to implement the fanciest optimization that
有意识地决定不实施最花哨的优化
is known in the research literature. And that's kind of an unfortunate thing from
在研究文献中是已知的。这是一件很不幸的事情
my point of view being somebody who's really likes compilers and spent a lot of
我的观点是，我是一个真正喜欢编译器的人，并且花了很多时间
time thinking about optimization. And maybe it's a little bit hard to accept for
花时间思考优化问题。也许这有点让人难以接受
the professional compiler researchers that, that people don't always want to
专业的编译器研究人员认为，人们并不总是想要
implement the latest and greatest optimization. But it's worth understanding
实施最新最大的优化。但这是值得理解的
why that might not be the case and it boils down essentially to software
为什么可能不是这样，归根结底是软件
engineering. Some of these optimizations are really hard to implement, I mean
工程学。我的意思是，其中一些优化确实很难实现
they're just complicated to implement. Some of the optimizations are costly in
它们只是实施起来很复杂。某些优化在以下方面代价高昂
compilation time. So even though the compiling happens offline, it is not part
编译时间。因此，即使编译是离线进行的，它也不是
of the running of the program, you know the programmer still has to wait while the
在程序的运行过程中，您知道程序员仍然需要等待
optimizing compiler compiles, does its compilation and if it takes hours or in
优化编译器编译，进行编译，如果需要几个小时或在
some cases days, to optimize a program, you know, that's not necessarily great.
在某些情况下，要优化一个程序，你知道，这不一定是很好的。
And, some of these optimizations have low pay off. They might, always improve the
而且，其中一些优化的回报很低。他们可能，总是会改善
program, but they might only do it by a very small amount and unfortunately, many
程序，但是他们可能只做很小的量，不幸的是，很多
of the fanciest optimizations in the literature have all three of these
在文献中最奇特的优化中，这三个都有
properties. They're complicated, they take a long time to run, and they don't do very
属性。它们很复杂，需要很长时间才能跑完，而且它们做得不是很好
much. And so it's not so surprising That and not all of these to get implemented in
很多。所以并不令人惊讶的是，并不是所有的这些都能在
production compilers. And this actually, you kn ow points out what the real goal is
生产编译器。而这实际上，你知道指出了真正的目标是什么
in optimization. What we really want is maximum benefit for minimum cost. We're
在优化方面。我们真正想要的是以最小的成本获得最大的利益。我们是
really talking about a cost benefit ratio. So, like optimization costs a certain
真正谈论的是成本效益比。所以，像优化一样需要一定的成本
amount, in code complexity, complexity of the compiler In programmer time I mean
我的意思是，在代码复杂度方面，编译器在程序员时间内的复杂度
waiting for the compiler to run and, and the benefit, the amount that it improves
等待编译器运行，以及它改进的数量
the program has to be sufficient to justify those costs.
该计划必须足以证明这些成本是合理的。